Guide to the Nancy Colberg research collection on Wallace Stegner 1942-1996 1942-1996
Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
Nancy Colberg research collection on Wallace Stegner
1942-1996
Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections P.O. Box 173320, Centennial Mall Montana State University
Colberg, Nancy
Collection 2443
3.2 linear feet
The Wallace Stegner Research Collection consists of periodicals and newspapers (including clippings) by and about Wallace Stegner throughout his prolific writing career. Besides his large body of monographic works, he wrote fictional short stories; accounts based on his childhood in the west; articles on writing, conservation, western U.S. history, Mormons, the wilderness, and politics (primarily of the west and its future).
Box 1
Box 2
Box 3
Box 4
Box 5
Box 6
Box 7
Box 8
Nancy Colberg, a librarian, author of Wallace Stegner: A Descriptive Bibliography (Confluence Press Inc., 1990) and retired owner of Willow Creek Books, a used and rare book store in Denver, Colorado, collected one of the country's largest collections of publications written by and about Wallace Stegner - writer of fiction, history and essays on the U.S. west including: history, literature, public policy and conservation. In 1982, Colberg met Stegner and, as she collected works by him, she realized a need for an in-depth descriptive bibliography. When Stegner learned of her project, he granted her access to his books and papers and gave her a corner desk in his study when she visited at his California home. He also wrote letters of introduction for her to libraries and other sources of materials for her research. Colberg eventually gathered 54 original letters and postcards from Stegner written to her, photocopies of 370 Stegner letters written to others, and about 600 books, journals and article offprints created by or written about Stegner. All of Colberg's collected monographs have been individually cataloged and are available in Special Collections. The journals, articles, correspondence and other miscellaneous materials by and about Wallace Stegner are included in this collection. A second and smaller private collection of monographs and journal articles belonging to the late Thomas H. Watkins, who intended on writing a biography of Stegner, has been incorporated into this collection.
This collection of published materials contains periodicals and newspapers (including clippings) by and about Wallace Stegner throughout his prolific writing career. Besides his large body of monographic works, he wrote fictional short stories; accounts based on his childhood in the west; articles on writing, conservation, western U.S. history, Mormons, the wilderness, and politics (primarily of the west and its future). The collection is organized into five series which, for the most part, conform to the arrangement of the sections in Colberg's published bibliography of Stegner. Series 1 contains Stegner articles from periodicals and newspapers. Series 2 is an assortment of short stories in periodicals. Series 3 consists of published interviews; articles about Stegner's body of work; book reviews by and about Stegner; miscellaneous materials containing lectures, addresses, reprints and quotes from his writings; articles by his son, Page and book announcements and collecting information. Series 4 contains the letters and postcards from Wallace Stegner to Nancy Colberg. Series 5 is a set of business correspondence between publishers, individuals, educational institutions and others and Wallace Stegner.
Series 1: Articles in periodicals and newspapers, 1944-1983
Series 2: Short stories in periodicals and newspapers, 1942-1987
Series 3: Miscellaneous published materials by and about Wallace Stegner, 1942-1996
Series 4: Correspondence from Wallace Stegner to Nancy Colberg, 1982-1990
Series 5: Business correspondence for selected publications of Wallace Stegner, 1943-1976
This collection is open for research.
Nancy Colberg sold her collection of the publications and correspondence of Wallace Stegner to Montana State University on June 30, 2001.
Stegner, Wallace, 1909-1993; Stegner, Wallace, 1909-1993--Bibliography; Stegner, Page; Stegner, Wallace, 1909-1993; Watkins, Thomas H. (Thomas Henry), d. 2000
West (U.S.)--In literature--Bibliography
Civic Activism; Literature; Religion
Articles; Book reviews; Correspondence; Lectures; Short stories; Interviews
- Articles in periodicals and newspapers, 1944-1983; 1
  This partial physical bibliography of articles by Wallace Stegner which appeared in periodicals and newspapers between July 1944 and winter of 1993 has been arranged chronologically and conforms to the arrangement in Section C of Nancy Colberg's Wallace Stegner: A Descriptive Bibliography.
  - 1944-1955 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - "Who Persecutes Boston?", (July 1944)
      Atlantic, 174 (July 1944), p. 45-52.
    - "I Dreamed I Saw Joe Hill Last Night", (Spring 1947)
      Pacific Spectator, 1 (Spring 1947), p. 184-87.
    - "Backroads River", (January 1948)
      Atlantic, 181 (January 1948), p. 56-64.
    - "Pattern for Demagogues", (Autumn 1948)
      Pacific Spectator, 2 (Autumn 1948), p. 399-411.
    - "The Teaching and Study of Writing", (Spring 1950)
      Western Review, 14 (Spring 1950), p. 165-179.
    - "Powell and the Names on the Plateau", (Spring 1953)
      Western Humanities Review, 7 (Spring 1953), p. 105-110.
    - "We Are Destroying Our National Parks,", (June 13, 1955)
      Sports Illustrated, 3 (June 13, 1955), p. 28-29, 44-46.
    - "Quiet Earth, Big Sky", (October 1955)
      American Heritage, 6 (October 1955), p. 22-27.
  - 1956-1959 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - "Twenty Years of Western Review: a Series of Recollections", (Winter 1956)
      Western Review, 20 (Winter 1956), p. 87-89.
    - "America's Mightiest Playground", (July 1956)
      Holiday, 20 (July 1956), p. 34-43, 122-125
    - "History Comes to the Plains", (June 1957)
      American Heritage, 8 (June 1957), p. 14-19, 108-111
    - "The Mounties at Fort Walsh", (July 1958)
      Atlantic, 202 (July 1958), p. 50-54
    - "California's Gold Rush Country", (August 1958)
      Holiday, 24 (August 1958), p. 64-69, 127
    - "The Town Dump", (October 1959)
      Atlantic, 204 (October 1959), p. 78-80
    - "To a Young Writer", (November 1959)
      Atlantic, 204 (November 1959), p. 88-91
  - 1962-1965 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - "Child of the Far Frontier", (September 1962)
      Horizon, 5 (September 1962), p. 94-95
    - "Song to the Morning Star", (Winter 1965)
      American West, 2 (Winter 1965), p. 23
    - "Good-bye to All That!", (March 1965)
      Atlantic, 215 (March 1965), p. 119
    - "On the Writing of History", (Fall 1965)
      American West, 2 (Fall 1965), p. 6-13. Note: Speech delivered at University of Utah June, 1965. Reprinted as a keepsake from the American West for the Helena meeting of the Western History Association, October, 1965.
  - 1967-1969 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - "Introduction", (February 1967)
      American West, 4 (February 1967), p. 4-5
    - "Commentary", (March 15, 1967)
      American West Review, 1 (March 15, 1967), p. 12
    - "History, Myth, and the Western Writer", (May 1967)
      American West, 4 (May 1967), p. 61-62, 76-79. Note: Reprinted as introduction to Great Western Short Stories (J. Golden Taylor - 1967)
    - "Commentary", (June 15, 1967)
      American West Review, 1 (June 15, 1967), p. 14
    - "For Their Own Sake, and Ours", (September 15, 1967)
      American West Review, 1 (September 15, 1967), p. 14
    - "Commentary: A Matter of Continuity", (December 1, 1967)
      American West Review, 1 (December 1, 1967), p. 12
    - "Beginning!", (January-February 1968)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 19 (January-February 1968), p. 11-22. (Chapter 1)
    - "Chapter 2", (March-April 1968)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 19 (March-April 1968), p. 15-21
    - "Chapter 3", (May-June 1968)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 19 (May-June 1968), p. 8-15
    - "Chapter 4", (July-August 1968)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 19 (July-August 1968), p. 8-15
    - "Chapter 6", (November-December 1968)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 19 (November-December 1968), p. 4-11
    - "Chapter 7", (January-February 1969)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 20 (January-February 1969), p. 12-21
    - "Chapter 8", (March-April 1969)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 20 (March-April 1969), p. 10-21
    - "Chapter 9", (May-June 1969)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 20 (May-June 1969), 22-31
    - "Chapter 10", (July-August 1969)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 20 (July-August 1969), p. 20- 27
  - 1969-1973 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - "Conservation Equals Survival", (December 1969)
      American Heritage, 21 (December 1969), p.12-15
    - "Chapter 12", (January-February 1970)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 21 (January-February 1970), p. 17-21
    - "Chapter 13", (March-April 1970)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 21 (March-April 1970), p. 9-17
    - "Chapter 14", (July-August 1970)
      (DISCOVERY!) Aramco World Magazine, 21 (July-August 1970), p. 8-21
    - "Bernard DeVoto and the Mormons: Three Letters", (Autumn-Winter 1971)
      Dialogue: A Journal of Mormon Thought, 6 (Autumn-Winter 1971), p. 39-47
    - "Thoughts in a Dry Land", (September 1972)
      Westways, 64 (September 1972), p. 14-19, 58
    - "Historian by Serendipity", (August 1973)
      American Heritage, 24 (August 1973), p. 28-32, 92-96
    - "The Coast of Oregon", (Autumn 1973)
      Travel and Leisure, 3 (Autumn 1973), p. 41-43
    - "This New Man, the American", (Fall/Winter 1973)
      Stanford Magazine, 1 (Fall/Winter 1973), p. 14-19. Note: Appears as "Variations on a Theme of Discontent," which Stegner delivered as the commencement address at Utah State University June 3, 1972. Also published as a separate pamphlet by Utah State University Press, 1972.
  - 1973-1978 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - "DeVoto's Western Adventures", (November 1973)
      American West, 10 (November 1973), p. 20-27
    - "Letter from Canada", (January 1974)
      American West, 11 (January 1974), p. 28-30
    - "Down Among the Archives", (April 1975)
      The Imprint (of the Stanford Libraries), 1 (April 1975), p. 16-19
    - "Breadloaf in the 40's", (Summer 1975)
      Middlebury College News Letter, 49 (Summer 1975), p. 30-31
    - "Depression Pop", (September 1975)
      Esquire, 84 (September 1975), p. 79-83, 154
    - "The Writer's Sense of Place", (Autumn 1975)
      South Dakota Review, 13 (Autumn 1975), p. 49-52
    - "Rocky Mountain Country", (April 1978)
      Atlantic, 241 (April 1978), p. 44-64, 71-91. (By Wallace and Page Stegner)
  - 1979-1981 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - "Getting to Know the National Domain", (February 1979)
      American Heritage, 30 (February 1979), p. 60-62
    - "Worst Government in the World-Except for the Others", (September 22, 1980)
      U.S. News, 89 (September 22, 1980), p. 53-54
    - "The Geography of Hope", (December 1980)
      Living Wilderness, 44 (December 1980), p. 12-17
    - "By Chaos Out of Dream", (February/March 1981)
      American Heritage, 32 (February/March 1981), p. 4-13
    - "Xanadu by the Salt Flats", (June/July 1981)
      American Heritage, 32 (June/July 1981), p. 81-89
    - "Land: America's History Teacher", (Summer 1981)
      Living Wilderness, 45 (Summer 1981), p. 4-13
    - "Water Warnings, Water Futures", (Fall 1981)
      Plateau, 53 (Fall 1981), p. 2-3
    - "Down the Upper Mississippi", (September 1981)
      Country Journal, 8 (September 1981), p. 74-86
  - 1981-1983 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - "High Plateaus", (September/October 1981)
      Sierra, 66 (September/October 1981), p. 8-17
    - "Dead Heart of the West: Utah's Great Salt Lake", (November 1981)
      Rocky Mountain Magazine, 3 (November 1981), p. 56-59
    - "The Long Road from Byblos", (February 1982)
      Soundings, 13 (February 1982), p. 5-19
    - "George R. Stewart, Western Writer", (March/April 1982)
      American West, 19 (March/April 1982), p. 64, 67-69
    - "Life with My Ancestors," American Heritage", (August/September 1982)
      American Heritage, 33 (August/September 1982), p. 21
    - "The Best Idea We Ever Had", (Spring 1983)
      Wilderness, 46 (Spring 1983), p. 4-13
  - 1983-1985 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - "Two Artists, Two Friends: A Conversation", (Spring 1983)
      Stanford Magazine, 11 (Spring 1983), p. 50-55
    - "Ansel Adams and the Search for Perfection", (January 1984)
      Arizona Highways, 60 (January 1984), p. 11-13
    - "Owen Wister: Creator of the Cowboy Myth", (January/February 1984)
      American West, 21 (January/February 1984), p. 48-52
    - "Ansel Adams 1902-1984", (Summer 1984)
      Wilderness, 48 (Summer 1984), p. 2-3
    - "Ansel's Last Birthday Party", (August 1984)
      California, (August 1984), p. 74-75, 83, 123
    - "Strange Encounter", (October 7, 1984)
      California Living, (October 7, 1984), p. 24-25. (An October 18, 1984 letter to Nancy from Wally tucked inside.)
    - "Claiming Our Cultural Heritage", (Spring 1985)
      Nebraska Humanist, 8 (Spring 1985), p. 45-54
    - "Living on Our Principal", (Spring 1985)
      Wilderness, 48 (Spring 1985), p.15-21
    - "Rivers of My Mind", (March 24, 1985)
      San Francisco Chronicle (Great Escapes), (March 24, 1985), p. 28-30
    - "Bernard DeVoto", (August 1985)
      Western American Literature, 20 (August 1985), p. 151-164
  - 1985-1987 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - "The Power of Homely Detail", (August/September 1985)
      American Heritage, 36 (August/September 1985), p. 62-69
    - "The Scandinavians Among Us", (October 1985)
      Reader's Digest, 127 (October 1985), p. 130-134
    - "The Function of Aridity", (Fall 1987)
      Wilderness, 51 (Fall 1987), p. 14-18
    - "Who Are the Westerners?", (December 1987)
      American Heritage, 38 (December 1987), p. 34-41
  - 1989-1993 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - "Our Common Domain", (September/October 1989)
      Sierra, 74 (September/October 1989), p. 42-47
    - "It All Began with Conservation", (April 1990)
      Smithsonian, 21 (April 1990), p. 34-43
    - "The Winter of Our Content", (February 1991)
      Life, 14 (February 1991), p. 87
    - Excerpt from "Thoughts in a Dry Land", (Winter 1993)
      Current Books Magazine, 1 (Winter 1993), p. 78-80, 95
- Short stories in periodicals and newspapers, 1942-1987; 2
  Wallace Stegner wrote many short stories which were published in magazines and newspapers and won many awards. This series has seven of these publications arranged chronologically and conforms to the arrangement in Section D of Nancy Colberg's Wallace Stegner: A Descriptive Bibliography.
  - 1942-1987 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - "Two Rivers", (June 1942)
      Atlantic, 169 (June 1942), p. 745-752. (Second Prize 0. Henry Awards, 1942. Many textbook appearances.)
    - "The Turtle at Home", (April 1943)
      Atlantic, 171 (April 1943), p. 123, 127. Abridged version of "My Pet Achilles, the Amusing Turtle," "Balance His, Swing Yours," Rocky Mountain Review, 10 (Autumn 1945), p. 32-38.
    - "Saw Gang, (October 1945)
      Atlantic, 176 (October 1945), p. 82-84."Genesis," Contact, 2 (April 1959), p. 85-167. (A Novella)
    - "Three Stories by Wallace Stegner", (October 12, 1984)
      Scholastic Scope, 33 (October 12, 1984), p. 1-10. Simplified stories from The Women on the Wall: ("Chip Off the Old Block," "The Foreigner," and "In the Twilight.")
    - "Amicitia", (Centennial Issue 1987)
      Sequoia, 31 (Centennial Issue 1987), p. 16-25
- Miscellaneous published materials by and about Wallace Stegner, 1942-1996; 3
  This series contains a miscellaneous assortment of published items by and about Wallace Stegner. They have been arranged by category and therein chronologically. Included are: book reviews by Stegner; interviews of Stegner; addresses, pamphlet articles, lectures and quotes by Wallace Stegner; periodical and newspaper articles on Stegner's works; reviews of Stegner books; materials based on Stegner's work; and obituaries and tributes to Stegner. Also included are two articles by Page Stegner (his son) and a collection of book promotion and collecting materials. Some but not all of these materials were listed in Section E and the Appendix of in Nancy Colberg's Wallace Stegner: A Descriptive Bibliography.
  - Book reviews written by Wallace Stegner: (Box-folder 5/1)
    - "No Day of Triumph" by J. Saunders Redding, (December 1942)
      Atlantic 170 (December 1942), p. 130
    - "The True Adventures of John Steinbeck" by Jackson J. Benson, (January 1, 1984)
      Los Angeles Times, Book Review Section (January 1, 1984), p. 1
    - "Sacred Cows at the public Trough" by Denzel and Nancy Ferguson, (Spring 1984)
      The Amicus Journal, 5 (Spring 1984), p. 45-47
    - "Inventing the Dream, California Through the Progressive Era" by Kevin Starr, (February 24, 1985)
      New York Times Book Review, (February 24, 1985), p.1, 33
  - Published Interviews with Wallace Stegner: (Box-folder 5/2)
    - "American Regions" (Stegner on "Mormon Country"), (December 19, 1942)
      Northwestern University on the Air, (December 19, 1942), radio conversation over the Columbia Broadcasting System
    - "Conversation with Wallace Stegner", (Spring 1971)
      South Dakota Review, 9 (Spring 1971), p. 45-57. (This issue also has a critique of Stegner and "Big Rock Candy Mountain" by Lois Phillips Hudson on p. 3-13)
    - "Times Prisoners" an interview with Wallace Stegner, (Summer 1976)
      Southwest Review, (Summer 1976), p. 252-267
    - "Time is not just Chronicle" and interview with Wallace Stegner, (Spring 1979)
      Massachusetts Review, 20 (Spring 1979), p. 127-139
    - "An Interview with Wallace Stegner", (January-February 1980)
      Sunstone, A Unique Mormon Magazine, 5 (January-February 1980), p. 7-11
    - "Something Elemental about the West Comes Pushing Through His Prose", (January 4, 1981)
      (?) Review, (January 4, 1981), p.10-11
    - "In the Company of Wallace Stegner", (July 1981)
      San Francisco Magazine, (July 1981), cover, p. 38-43
  - Miscellaneous publications of addresses, articles, lectures and quotes by Wallace Stegner: (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Poster. "The Sound of Mountain Water", 1954
      Standard Oil of California Western Scenes, 1954. More than 1,000,000 free copies were distributed to motorists and visitors in the West, May through September 1955.
    - Keepsake. "On the Writing of History", October 1965
      a keepsake from The American West for the Helena meeting of the Western History Association
    - Program. "The Book and the Great Community", May 17, 1968
      program with full text of dedicatory address presented by Stegner at the Library Dedication Exercises, University of Utah
    - Pamphlet. "Variations on a Theme of Discontent", June 3, 1972
      pamphlet published by Utah State University Press, Logan, Utah, containing the full text of the commencement address presented
    - Program. "A Dedication", April 13, 1977
      program with full text of dedicatory address presented by Stegner at the Library Dedication Exercises, University of Arizona
    - "The Twilight of Self - Reliance: Frontier Values and Contemporary America", February 25, 1980
      full text of Tanner Lectures on Human Values delivered at University of Utah
    - "The Gift of Wilderness", June 27, 1981
      remarks at the Annual Meeting of the Trust for Public Land
    - The 1983 Western Wilderness Calendar, 1982
      by Dream Garden Press. February - Stegner quotations
    - The 1984 Western Wilderness Calendar, 1983
      by Dream Garden Press. December - Stegner
    - Quotation from The Sound of Mountain Water: "By such a river it is impossible to believe that one will ever be tired or old."
    - The 1985 Western Wilderness Calendar, 1984
      by Dream Garden Press. November - Stegner
    - "On the Writing of History", February 19, 1989
      (2 copies) reprinted especially for his 80th birthday, February 19, 1989 (accompanied by invitation to celebration and a letter to Nancy Colberg from Sylvia A.)
  - Periodical articles on Stegner's body of work: (Box-folder 5/4)
    - "The Western Experience in American Literature", (circa 1977)
      ed. By Merrill Lewis and L. L. Lee, (circa 1977), p. 135-143
    - "Wallace Stegner's Vision of Wilderness", (August 1983)
      Western American Literature, 18 (August 1983), p. 133-142
    - "Wallace Stegner Number", (Winter 1985)
      entire issue: South Dakota Review, 23 (Winter 1985). (Includes a letter to Nancy Colberg inside.)
    - Where would you take a guest to sightsee in California, (June 1985)
      California, (June 1985), p. 119
    - "Typewritten on Both Sides", (September 1987)
      photocopy of article by T. H. Watkins in Audubon, (September 1987), p. 88-103
    - "Thoughts on Western Writers" by John Milton, (Fall 1989)
      Writers' Forum, 15 (Fall 1989), p. 1-20
    - Wallace Stegner's Version of Pastoral" by Russell Burrows, (May 1990)
      Western American Literature, 25 (May 1990), p. 15-25
    - "Eastering': Wallace Stegner's Love Affair with Vermont in Crossing to Safety" by Jackson J. Benson, (May 1990)
      Western American Literature, 25 (May 1990), p. 27-33
    - "Western History Association Prize Recipient, 1991: Wallace Stegner", (May 1991)
      Western Historical Quarterly, 22 (May 1991), p. 137-141
  - Newspaper articles about Stegner's work: (Box-folder 6/1)
    - "Writers of the Purple Sage" by Russell Martin, (December 27, 1981)
      New York Times Magazine, (December 27, 1981, sect. 6), p. 18-22, 40-43
    - "Mary and Wallace Stegner, Valentines for 55 years", (February 8, 1989)
      Los Altos Town Crier, (February 8, 1989), front page, p. 6, 16
    - "A New Look at Wallace Stegner: Conservationist or Preservationist", (September 3, 1991)
      Denver Post, (September 3, 1991), p. 7B
    - Ralph V. Hurlburt and Dorothea Hurlburt "Writing into the Sunset", (February 12, 1992)
      Washington Post, (February 12, 1992), 3 pages
    - "The West Needs More of Stegner's Stickers'", (April 5, 1992)
      Denver Post, (April 5, 1992), p. 3-I
    - "In the West with Wallace Stegner", (May 24, 1992)
      San Francisco Chronicle, This World, (May 24, 1992), front page, p. 11-13
    - Denver Post, (February 2, 1997)
      Empire, Magazine of the West, (February 2, 1997), p. 12. Within article "The Mystery of Everett Ruess."
  - Reviews of Stegner Books: (Box-folder 6/2)
    - "The Uneasy Chair: A Biography of Bernard DeVoto," review by C. L. Sonnichsen, (July 1974)
      Western Historical Quarterly, 5 (July 1974), p. 361-362
    - "One Way to Spell Man," review by Roderick Nordell, (March 17, 1982)
      Christian Science Monitor, (March 17, 1982), p. 17
    - "Crossing to Safety," review by James R. Hepworth, (November/December 1987)
      The Bloomsbury Review, 7 (November/December 1987), p. 11
    - "Collected Stories of Wallace Stegner," review by Jane Helm Maddock, (August 1991)
      Western American Literature, 26 (August 1991), p. 149-150
  - Materials based on Wallace Stegner and his works: (Box-folder 6/3)
    - "Study Guide for Angle of Repose' by Wallace Stegner" by Janet L. Jacobsen, 1986
    - "Wallace Stegner and the Continental Vision", May 3-5, 1996
      brochure for a symposium of the Wisconsin Academy of Sciences, Arts and Letters of May 3-5, 1996
  - Obituaries and tributes: (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Letter to Mary by T. H. Watkins, April 21, 1993
    - Bloomsbury Review, (July/August 1993)
      13 (July/August 1993), cover, p. 8-9
    - Broadside of San Francisco Bay Area Book Council for a tribute to Wallace Stegner, April 29, 1993
    - Review of "Wallace Stegner: His Life and Work," Jackson J. Benson by James R. Kincaid, (November 10, 1996)
      New York Times Book Review, (November 10, 1996), p. 69